<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>JFeggio</title>
    <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on JFeggio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 13:40:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jfeggio.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linear Programming - Investment funds</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/programacionlineal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 13:40:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/programacionlineal/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Mathematical Model Solution Introduction Language used: Excel (Solver add-on)
Task to solve:
Money to be invested: $5.000.000 Investment type Earning to be achieved (per year) Investment limit (milions) Consumer credit 7% 1 Corporative bonds 11% 1.5 Gold deposits 19% 2.5 Housing loans 12% 1.7 Additional Limits:
Investment type Investment out of all funds Consumer credit Maximum 15% Housing loans &amp;amp; Gold deposits Minimum	5% Mathematical Model Decision Variables:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markov Chains - Collection Strategy</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/markovchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 13:40:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/markovchain/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Mathematical Model Solution Introduction Language used: R (Markov Chains package)
Task to solve: Analyze the Bad Payers situation.
Transitional matrix with this components: Group A (good payers)
30% will stay in this category 30% will become a bad payer (Group B) The rest will pay all overdue Group B (bad payers)
10% goes to the default stage 20% pays the overdue 40% will stay in Group B 30% will go to Group A D (default): Default</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Descriptive Analysis of Airbnb accomodations in Bologna</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 20:38:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>Language used: R
Database used: &amp;ldquo;listing.csv&amp;rdquo; from the website http://insideairbnb.com/get-the-data/ composed by a mix of 18 qualitative and quantitative variables and 3896 cases.
Packages used: dplyr: to obtain a general descriptive analysis of the data. ggplot2: to create graphs ggmap: to be able to show maps RColorBrewer: to assign colors to the heatmap visualization osmdata: to obtain the geographic coordinates of the city of Bologna hrbrthemes: to obtain more ggplot themes Variables description:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Happiness Report - A Cluster Analysis [1/2]</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/whr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 20:38:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/whr1/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Data Wrangling Descriptive Analysis Outliers Cluster Analysis Number of Clusters Hierarchical Analysis Non-Hierarchical Analysis ANOVA Conclusion (PCA) Introduction Language used: R
Database used: The World Happiness report from 2021 which is a global survey data to report how people evaluate their own lives in more than 150 countries worldwide.
Packages used: dplyr: to obtain a general descriptive analysis of the data. corrplot: to create correlation matrix readxl: to import the database (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Happiness Report - A Principal Components Analysis [2/2]</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/whr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 20:38:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/whr2/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Descriptive Analysis Outliers Principal Components Analysis Eigenvalues Loadings Correlation between components Components 1 (Quality of Life) and 2 (Economy/Corruption) Components 1 (Quality of Life) and 3 (Social Support/Corruption) Components 2 (Economy/Corruption) and 3 (Social Support/Corruption) Conclusion Introduction Please refer to the Introduction of &amp;ldquo;World Happiness Report - A Cluster Analysis [1/2]&amp;rdquo; as this is the second part of this work.
Descriptive Analysis Please refer to the Descriptive Analysis of &amp;ldquo;World Happiness Report - A Cluster Analysis [1/2]&amp;rdquo; as this is the second part of this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/nlp_reddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/nlp_reddit/</guid>
      <description>git&amp;mdash; title: &amp;ldquo;Use of Anglicisms on Spanish-speaking Latin American subreddits on the social media platform Reddit &amp;quot; date: 2023-12-22T20:38:41+01:00 draft: false tags: [&amp;ldquo;uni&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;natural language processing&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;data wrangling&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;nlp&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;spacy&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;nltk&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;topic modelling&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;text-mining&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;kmeans&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;api&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;reddit&amp;rdquo;] categories: [&amp;ldquo;uni&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;python&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;multivariate analysis&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;unsupervised machine learning&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;nlp&amp;rdquo;] Table of Contents Introduction Data Wrangling Descriptive Analysis Frequency of English words by year (2016-2023) Named-entity recognition (NER) and Topic Modelling NER Topic Modelling Cluster Analysis K-Means Influence of US by year Introduction Language used: Python</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
