<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>numpy on JFeggio</title>
    <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/tags/numpy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in numpy on JFeggio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 20:38:41 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jfeggio.github.io/tags/numpy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bank Marketing Audit</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/bank_audit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 20:38:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/bank_audit/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Data Quality Analysis Loans Customers Segmentation Law 26.951 Results Presence of Missing Values in the Dataset Presence of Missing Values in the Dataset Low Success Rate in Marketing Campaigns Risk of Default Among Borrowers Non-Compliance with Law 26.951 Introduction Language used: Python
Libraries used
Library Description pandas Data manipulation and analysis to work with structured data numpy For numerical operations to work on large and multi-dimensional arrays and matrices matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Prices Prediction with Regression Modelling and Features Selection</title>
      <link>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/house_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 20:38:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jfeggio.github.io/posts/house_prediction/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Data Wrangling Model Introduction Language used: Python
Goal: Prediction of house prices.
Data used: Dataset from Properati website (https://www.properati.com.ar/). Two datasets: one for training (dataframe: dfef) and one for testing (dataframe: dfp)
Link to the Dataset: https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/jluza92/argentina-properati-listings-dataset-20202021/data (1gb)
Libraries used
Library Description pandas Data manipulation and analysis to work with structured data numpy For numerical operations to work on large and multi-dimensional arrays and matrices sklearn used for machine learning algorithms for classification, regression, clustering, dimensionality reduction matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
